



Mohammad Shahin Shah

Date of birth: 3 Mar 2000 | Nationality: Bangladeshi | Gender: Male | Phone number:

(+880) 1568022438 (Mobile) | **Phone number:** (+880) 1521537475 (Work) | **Phone number:**

(+880) 1846830882 (Home) | Email address: mohammadshahinshah3@gmail.com | Email address:

mohammadshahin@ieee.org | Website: https://mohammadshahin.com/ | Website:

https://mohammadshahin.me/ | Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mohammadshahinshah03/ |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammadshahinshah/

WhatsApp Messenger: +8801521537475

Address: Bhuiyaan Manjeel, Sobahanbag, Sitakunda, 4310, Chattogram, Bangladesh

(Home)

ABOUT ME

I am studying Computer Science and Engineering at the International Islamic University Chittagong, specially interested in the field of computer vision and deep learning. In my thesis, I work on fire classification with depth wise separable convolutions along with Inception and attention mechanisms to boost model accuracy. I have a wide range of professional experience in graphic design — I have been professionally a Senior Executive and Graphic Designer at Requin BD, Excite AI to respectively create social media visuals that have had impact, and trained interns. In my role as Secretary of IEEE CS BDC's Web & IT Committee, I coordinate the whole team and lead digital initiatives to augment technical engagement. My career hope is to merge my current AI skill and computer science knowledge into research positions to generate innovation and practical solutions regarding technology. I want to make a research based artificial intelligence and computer science career.

WORK EXPERIENCE

3 MAY 2024 - 31 OCT 2024 Dhaka, Bangladesh

GRAPHIC DESIGNER EXCITE AI

Created engaging social media graphics that drove user engagement and increased online visibility

5 MAY 2024 - 2 AUG 2024 Khulna, Bangladesh

SENIOR EXECUTIVE GRAPHIC DESIGNER REQUIN BD

Teamwork, Checking Designs, and instructing new INTERNS.

25 DEC 2023 - 31 MAR 2024 Khulna, Bangladesh

JUNIOR EXECUTIVE GRAPHIC DESIGNER REQUIN BD

Teamwork, Checking Designs, and instructing new INTERNS.

1 SEP 2023 – 30 DEC 2023 Khulna, Bangladesh

GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERN REQUIN BD

I created graphics and visual content for social media campaigns while learning to fit myself into the professional environment.

2 MAR 2024 - CURRENT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SECRETARY IEEE CS BDC WEB & IT COMMITTEE

As Secretary of the IEEE CS BDC Web & IT Committee, I help facilitate and coordinate our team efforts, manage communications, and help lead digital projects that increase the committee's engagement and technical endeavors.

5 FEB 2024 - CURRENT Dhaka, Bangladesh

CO-ORDINATOR, GRAPHIC TEAM IEEE COMPUTER SOCIETY BANGLADESH CHAPTER SECRETARIAT

I have demonstrated expertise in using Photoshop and Illustrator to create innovative graphics.

- Utilized extensive knowledge of Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator to create high-quality images.
- Generated digital image files for use in digital and traditional printing methods.

1 AUG 2023 - 30 AUG 2024 Chattogram, Bangladesh

HEAD OF DEPARTMENT CREATIVE AND DESIGN HULT PRIZE AT INTERNATIONAL ISLAMIC UNIVERSITY CHITTAGONG

- Promoted a culture of collaboration, continuous learning, and creativity.
- Guided creative direction in alignment with brand goals and ensured design projects met standards.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

1 APR 2020 - 30 DEC 2024 Chattogram, Bangladesh

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING International Islamic University Chittagong

Website https://www.iiuc.ac.bd/ | Level in EQF EQF level 6

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): BENGALI

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office

Microsoft Word | Microsoft Excel | Microsoft Powerpoint

Graphic Design

Adobe Illustrator | Adobe Photoshop | Canva

Video Editing & Motion Grahics

Adobe After Effects | Adobe Premier Pro

UX Design

Figma | Sketch

Programming Languages & Frameworks

C | C++ | Python | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | MongoDB | ReactJs | MySQL | SQL

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Literature

Traveling

Writing

Teaching